

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Software Engineer with a track record of delivering 10+ high-quality solutions within tight deadlines, achieving on average 20% improvement in performance optimization. Specialized in backend development with over half a decade of experience; collaborating on SAAS projects in a remote first, scrum environment that resulted in a 30% increase in overall efficiency. Committed to staying current with emerging technologies to drive innovation.

SKILLS

C#

Entity Framework

MongoDb

Nodejs

Azure

• Git

Typescript

SQL

Redis

EXPERIENCE

Team Lead Backend Engineering TENECE PROFFESSIONAL SERVICES | Lagos, Nigeria

Led a team of twenty to create SMCore: an overhaul of Tenece's Legacy School Management Solution. SMCore is an API based project written with .Net core and react on the front end.

- Setup a notification system which led to 40% increase in user interaction with SMCore
- Setup an nps rating system which led to a 20% increase in customer satisfaction with SMCore
- Upgraded and deployed <u>University of Nigeria Nsukka's portals</u> which resulted in a 100% elimination of downtime previously experienced by the portal
- Mentored junior developers, conducted thorough code reviews and facilitated weekly standup meetings to ensure code quality, adherence to coding standards, and optimal performance.

Senior Software Engineer

TENECE PROFFESSIONAL SERVICES | Lagos, Nigeria

February 2021 - June 2023

June 2023 - present

- Led a team of seven comprised of software developers, designers and quality assurance engineers in the development of Laviemedic: an enterprise management software for hospitals used to manage the entire life cycle of a patient activities in a hospital.
- Re hosted 10+ projects on Azure and setup CI/CD pipelines for all projects with Azure Pipelines. This facilitated 50% faster deployment times and about 90% smaller deployment sizes.
- Abstracted code and created nugets which led to a 100% decrease in time spent and bugs introduced while copying over code across projects.

Software Engineer

September 2019 - February 2021

TENECE PROFFESSIONAL SERVICES | Lagos, Nigeria

• Resolved engineering issues, fixed bugs and responded to on average 4 client requests a day encountered in multiple schools across the South-East of Nigeria.

Software Development Intern

April 2016 - December 2016

Genesys Tech Hub | Enugu, Nigeria

- Teamed up with fellow interns for the creation of a document management solution used for sharing files within an organization of 200 employees.
- Worked with fellow interns in the creation of a transcript management solution. This directly increased company revenue by 20% as it opened up a new stream of income
- Facilitated C# programming classes and mentored 40 interns as a volunteer in the Genesys BEZAO 2022 program (a
 way to give back to the community), equipping them with advanced skills that significantly enhanced their proficiency
 and set them up for success in their careers.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Engineering - Electrical Electronics Engineering Enugu State University of Science & Technology, Enugu Nigeria.

June 2019

PASSION PROJECT

Ekiexpress

August 2021 – September 2021

Worked with fellow Freelancers in the development of ekiexpress an online shopping Mall for the buying and selling of groceries executed using typescript and react.

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

- Award: 3rd Best learnable developer (Genesys Tech Hub's Internship program).
- Games: Ping Pong, Block Breaker